# Binod Adhikari

### Accounts officer at MNC Company

measbinod@yahoo.com

# Summary

I would welcome the chance to work as a part of a small, dynamic team where i could make a significant contribution while developing my skill yet further.

I believe that my strong management skills and education will make me a very competitive candidate for an organization .I am young and energetic candidate having to do attitude. I have passed Master Degree in Management (MBS) and currently i am engaged in CG. ELECTRONICS PVT . LTD, one of the renowned Manufacturing & Trading Business Organization ( Chaudhary Group ) of Nepal as Executive in Account Department. Also I have more than two years work experience of as Sales Cum Account Officer in Nepal Hilltop Industries P. Ltd. Also i have gained an internship program at Nabil Bank Limited at Remittance Business Unit of 2 months duration.

# Experience

#### Accouts Officer at Maccaferrri Nepal Pvt. Ltd

July 2013 - Present (1 year)

Maintain day to day account.

Tax invoicing

Payroll duties

Preparation of financial reports on supervision of CA

Preparation of vouchers

Reconciliation of cash/bank,costumer/vendor and balance confirmation.

Developing proper ledger and accounting groups.

Statuatory reporting and payment.

Administrative functions.

Computerized Accounting-Tally Erp9

Preparation of statistics and MIS Reports.

#### Executive - Account Department at CG Electronics Pvt Ltd-Chaudhary Group

September 2011 - July 2013 (1 year 11 months)

- Handling the Customer's Claim as of Sales and Accounting Disputes.
- Developing and Maintaining Proper General Ledger and Accounting Group
- Working with a team of Analyst and consultants and meet ever increasing client expectations.
- Preparation of Financial Reports for Account Receivable Management.
- Preparation of Financial report for the Government Tax (VAT, TDS, and Income Tax).
- Proper Guidelines and training to Junior Staff.
- Proper Handling of Debtor's Department
- Finalization of Journal Vouchers, Sales Return, Debit/ Credit Notes.

- Finalizing customer's Target Bonus and Incentive.
- Preparing Budget for Sales Promotion and Marketing.
- -Corporate Sales Management
- -Payable Management

#### Accountant at Nepal Hilltop Industries pvt ltd

October 2009 - September 2011 (2 years)

- Maintain Day to Day Account of Factory.
- Payroll Duties.
- Handling Petty Cash
- Preparation of Tax Invoice.
- Preparation of Journal Vouchers.
- Maintain Computerized Accounting.
- Handling Customer's Claim and Field Visit for Reconciliation.
- Assist to Chief Accountant for Final Account and Auditing Purpose.
- Product Costing and Inventory Management.
- Administrative Supervision of Factory.

1 recommendation available upon request

#### Intern at NABIL BANK LIMITED

March 2009 - May 2009 (3 months)

I have been worked as an intern for Remittance business unit of Western Union Money Transfer. I have learned about how the money is remmitted from one place to another and what is the process of sending and receiving money.

# Volunteer Experience

#### Treasurer at Nawa Shanti Development Commitee

# Projects

# Efficiency of Lending Policy" in Nepal SBI Bank and Everest Bank Limited of Nepal for the period 2008 to 2013

#### Members:Binod Adhikari

The study will be designed to overcome the issues relating to "Efficiency of Lending Policy" in SBI and EBL. This study will successfully explore the efficiency of lending in terms lending practices, trend of various components of loan and relationship of various component of lending policy and net profit. In this chapter, an attempt will be made to summarize the study and to make general conclusion based on the finding through data analysis.

#### Courses

## Master's, Management

Tribhuwan University

Master Degree in Financial Management Master Degree in Financial Management Masters in Financial Management

# Languages

**English** 

Nepali

Hindi

# Skills & Expertise

**Dealer Management** 

finacial transaction

**Financial Reporting** 

**Cost Accounting** 

**Fixed Assets** 

**Variance Analysis** 

**General Ledger** 

Accounting

**Internal Controls** 

**Financial Accounting** 

**Financial Audits** 

**Financial Analysis** 

**Internal Audit** 

**Bank Reconciliation** 

**Team Building** 

**Negotiation** 

**External Audit** 

**Accounts Receivable** 

**VAT** 

**Payroll** 

**Invoicing** 

**Account Reconciliation** 

**Teamwork** 

**Tax** 

**Project Planning** 

**MIS** 

**Budgets** 

**Marketing** 

**Operations Management** 

**Forecasting** 

**Sales** 

Analysis Business Strategy Management Microsoft Excel Inventory Management

### Education

## **Tribhuwan University**

Master's, Management, 2008 - 2013

## **Tribhuwan University**

Bachelor's, Management, 2005 - 2008

### Gramin Adarsha M. Campus

+2(12th Grade), Management, 2003 - 2005

#### TARUN SECONDARY SCHOOL BORAD OF NEPAL

10th Grade, Secondary level, 1996 - 2003

#### Interests

Friendship, travelling, reading novels, Listening Music

# **Binod Adhikari**

Accounts officer at MNC Company

measbinod@yahoo.com



# 1 person has recommended Binod

"Binod is hard working and good communicative with integrity. I wish him very success in his future endeavors."

- Rajendra Giri, was Binod's client

Contact Binod on LinkedIn